a lot of these AI tools are getting better
but that only means they can do
certain set of instructions
which are seen in data
you still need to provide AI what to do right
you still need to be able to describe it
and that
ability to describe what are the tasks AI should do
what are the programs to be written is still important
I think one job that will not be replaced by AI
is the ability to be curious
and go after hard problems
so for young people
my advice is not to be afraid of AI or worry
what skills to learn that AI may replace them with
but really be in that path of curiosity
I always begin the classes by asking questions
not writing down math equations right
not going into the details
but just intuitively
based on everything that you've seen
you've done what do you think
many times people already may be somewhat aware of this
so they have some intuitive ideas
so that already is a good starting point
and sometimes they are maybe really wrong
they have an intuition but that's a wrong intuition
but it's still okay
because intuitions are not always the only answer right
so I think a lot of it comes by asking questions
and now you can
use these AI tools to get answers very quickly
and also verify them
a lot of it comes from
being just like curious or interested
that could be one specific topic
and if somebody is interested in music they can
delve deeper into that
if somebody is interested in art
so it just has to that spark has to come from within
and I think giving students more the freedom to pursue
where they are passionate where they have a spark
I think is going to be the future
and that's the right thing
rather than forcing everybody to learn everything
so my mission is to constantly be curious
and learning and
not assume that
any problem is easy
I can't imagine a world
where scientists will be out of jobs
because the definition of a scientist
is somebody who tackles open problems right
so there are harder and harder problems to tackle
you know if you want to look
at the deep secrets of our universe
go down to the smallest scale
and understand at the atomic and sub atomic level how
matter is constructed to of course
level of galaxy and beyond
and understand how the universe is
put together there are still lots of open challenges
to me human agency is driving
AI to do something that you want it to be done
you have the agency as a human
to decide what tasks AI does
and then you're evaluating and you're in charge right
so you go and verify whether what AI
is saying is true or not
and then over time
provide that feedback to AI and make it get better
AI is a tool
it can both help curiosity
but also kill it depending on how it's used right
so for young people
my advice is not to be afraid of AI or worry
what skills to learn that AI may replace them with
but really be in that path of curiosity right
use AI as a tool to drive that curiosity
learn new skills new knowledge
and you can do that in a much more interactive way